# Reza Same'ei

Software Developer

### ABOUT ME

Yet another **Backend Developer** with about 8 yrs of experience in building software components, with an increasing interest on **Distributed Systems** and **Data Intensive** problems. I'm looking forward to gain more knowledge and experience on Big Data technologies and Distributed Systems design and implementation.

Tehran, Iran
+98 (912) 6662695
reza.samee@gmail.com
sameei.github.io
@ Github
@ Stackoverflow
@ LinkedIn
@ Skype

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

MARCH 2019 - PRESENT

TrialBlaze. Remotely; Perth, Australia

### Backend Developer

Build components to process non-standard ODM files and use **user defined logics**, expressed in a simple AST, to calculate entitlements and invoice, with a team of 4. Understaning the domain without adequate informtion and trying to design the system to maximum flexibilty was of our challenges.

Toolbox : Java, Drools, Docker, Postgres, Google Cloud, Go.

MARCH 2016 - DEC 2018

Bisphone. Tehran, Iran
Backend Developer

Lead a team of 2 to build and maintain more than 10 **data intensive** components, in different forms such as RPC services or **stream and batch** data processing jobs, to support main product: Bisphone, a messaging and voice-call application. Dealing with *consistency* issues amid microservices

and reaching better *high availability* rate were our main challenges while we were responsible to analyse and design for requested features from bussines team.

Toolbox : Scala, Akka, Flink, Cassandra, Kafka, MySQL, ELK.

OCT 2014 - Nov 2015

ImenPardis. Tehran, Iran Backend Developer

Implement backend services to support main product: frist version of Bisphone. I also deployed ELK

to use it as our monitoring platform at that time. Toolbox: Scala, Akka/Spary, MySQL, ELK, RabbitMQ, XMPP.

JULY 2013 - SEP 2014

Armaghan Rahe Talaie. Tehran, Iran

## Web Developer

Analyse requirement and Build a new Web based SMS Panel for company.

Toolbox: PHP, Doctrine ORM, MySQL, RabbitMQ, and JavaScript.

SEP 2011 - JULY 2013

Shiveh Co. Tehran, Iran Junior Web Developer

Started as a Junior, I was responsible to develop web based GIS application. But very soon I introduced Zend Framework, Propel ORM, CanJs (a javascript MVC framework), to the team, and I got more responsibility in team such as attending meetings with customers, and maintaining services (Linux). Toolbox: PHP, MySQL, JQuery, CanJS, Google Map API, SVN.

### **EDUCATION**

2009-2011 Associate Degree

Software Engineering; Technical & Vocational University, Karaj, Iran

#### COMMUNICATION SKILLS

ENGLISH B1

Persian Native

#### SOFTWARE SKILLS

Tools Scala, Akka, AkkaStream, Java,

Reactor, Git, SQL, Cassandra, Kafka, Apache Flink, Docker,

Google Cloud

CONCEPTS Distributed Systems,

Concurrency, Stream Processing, Functional Programming, OOP, DDD, Agility, JVM Performance

HANDS ON Spark, Hadoop, Cadence, Go,

Kubernettes, Pulsar, Zookeeper

Interests Data Intensive Applications,

Distributed System